<Document>
  # Influences

  Culists begin with two powerful inflences, and will gradually unlock more as they progress the Monument through its three stages.

  Once a cultist reaches the third stage, any time a cultist uses an influence, they have a chance to generate a telltale [color=#4cabb3]Malign Echo[/color]. These will fade after a short time, but may alert outsiders to the presence of your cult prematurely!

  Using Siphon Entropy will never generate a Malign Echo.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicEchoVfx" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  ## Starting Influences
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Siphon Entropy:[/bold][/color] Silently siphon entropy from your target. If the target is in critical condition, it will finish them off, but also give much more entropy.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Attune Influence:[/bold][/color] Check the cult's progress, and spend gathered entropy to unlock better, more powerful Influences.

  ## Special Influences
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Null Fragmentation:[/bold][/color] Transfer malign empowerment into a digital system, such as an AI Upload Console or Cyborg, corrupting it in the process. Doing so will expend empowerment.

  ## Unlockable Influences
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Null Glare:[/bold][/color] Emit a horrific pulse of cosmic light, slowing and disorienting everyone around you.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Abberant Lapse:[/bold][/color] Lapse your target's corporeal form, temporarily rendering it immutable, impassible, and frozen in place.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Force Ingress:[/bold][/color] Use a concentrated blast of power to force any lock open.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Unbound Step:[/bold][/color] You move relative only to the starless black - your movement is no longer affected by gravity.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Corrupt Matter:[/bold][/color] Pour malign power into an item, transforming it into something else. You can see what items can be transmuted by examining them.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Shunt Subjectivity:[/bold][/color] Shunt your target's mind out of their body and unto the cosmic dark, temporarily rendering their body mindless.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Astral Stride:[/bold][/color] Astral energy invigorates your movement, allowing you to run at incredible speed for a short amount of time.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Shatter Cognition:[/bold][/color] Share the Knowledge with an unsuspecting crewmember, leaving them with no choice but to join your cause.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Astral Nova:[/bold][/color] Hurl a large and disruptive blast of astral energy, wreaking havoc upon a large area.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Vacuous Imposition:[/bold][/color] Negate any incoming damage for a short time, at the cost of slowing down your movement.
</Document>
